# Christopher Hosler

Brooklyn, NY 11220 | 717-320-2497 | cmstie@gmail.com | GitHub | Blog | LinkedIn

### **SUMMARY**

Software developer experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with ten years experience in retail technology support. Possess strong skills in customer service and troubleshooting that can help client satisfaction and company effectiveness. Interested in using technology to make information easily accessible to everyone.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript, React, CSS, HTML, Git, ACMT, ACIT, MS Office, iWork

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

### NEO-Tracker - GitHub FrontEnd | GitHub BackEnd | Demo

An asteroid tracking web-application to view their position in the solar system in 3D, built using React and Ruby on Rails

- Pulled data using NASA's Open APIs to retrieve orbital and size data for selected asteroids
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens to handle authentication
- Created interactive 3D models using the Spacekit.js library

### ParkTracker - GitHub FrontEnd | GitHub BackEnd | Demo

An application to view information about National Parks with maps and weather, built using React and Ruby on Rails

- Utilized the National Park Service's API to collect photos and location information
- Integrated weather forecasts using information parsed form the OpenWeather API
- Created interactive maps of park locations using the MapBox library

## GameCollector - GitHub FrontEnd | GitHub BackEnd | Demo

A video game collecting web-application to show game data, including user playtime and ratings

- Parsed game data from the RAWG Video Game Database API
- Implemented a Ruby on Rails API to handle PostgreSQL database communication
- Implemented user interface using Javascript and HTML with CSS styling

### **EXPERIENCE**

Apple IncNew York, NYGenius Mac Technician06/2016 - Present

- Providing creative and innovative solutions to complex user based computer software and hardware issues
- Responsible for quarterly updates in technical knowledge, same-day repair completions, and continuous multi-tasking under a tight appointment system, taking 25 appointments a day

Apple Inc Cupertino, CA

X-ray Computed Tomography (CT) Spectroscopy Contractor

06/2018 - 11/2018

- Performed 3D X-ray scans of devices to assist the Failure Analysis team find potential points of failure in devices
- Assisted in the analysis of completed 3D X-ray scans and presented findings to the Engineering team

Best Buy
Deputy of Counter Intelligence - Geek Squad Supervisor

Harrisburg, PA 04/2010 - 06/2016

reputy of Counter intelligence - Geek Squad Supervisor

- Managed and developed a team, to drive revenue and customer satisfaction index to the highest in the district
- Acted as the ambassador of Geek Squad, to drive awareness of the brand and promoted protection plans/services
- As a Advanced Repair Agent provided face-to-face and phone-based support for clients to solve issues with PCs,
   Macs, and Mobile devices, over the first four years with the company

### The Vanguard School

Lake Wales, FL 08/2006 - 08/2008

Chemistry Teacher

- Oversaw and improved the school laboratory, ensured student safety, and provided new equipment
- Developed and taught a year long curriculum for Chemistry and Earth Science for students in grades 7-12

### **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** 

New York, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

05/2020 - 08/2020

Susquehanna University

Selinsgrove, PA

Bachelor of Science Degree in Chemistry